<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emacs on josiah&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/emacs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emacs on josiah&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>my opinions on task management and notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-opinions-on-notetaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-opinions-on-notetaking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note taking systems have come up at work a lot; flavor of the month applications (Roam Research! Obisidian!); whether you should write up notes in a private wiki; particular ideologies like &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zettelkasten&#34;&gt;Zettelkasten&lt;/a&gt; (ZTK) or &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Getting_Things_Done&#34;&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/a&gt; (GTD); etc. I have A Lot of Opinions about note taking and productivity, and wrote up a quick and dirty summary of options on apps / ideology for coworkers. This post is a longer form write up on task management, productivity systems, and notes generally from that original summary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>using org caldav with fastmail</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/using-org-caldav-with-fastmail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/using-org-caldav-with-fastmail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-sync-calendar-events-from-fastmail-to-your-org-agenda&#34;&gt;how to sync calendar events from fastmail to your org agenda&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;ve recently started a new job. i take a lot of notes, and I find it useful to take notes for each meeting along with some metadata about each meeting. the notes i obviously take as the meeting goes on, but the metadata is already in the meeting invite. rather than entering all of it manually for each meeting, I&amp;rsquo;ve had org-mode pull the meeting info for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>blogging on github pages with orgmode</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blogging-on-ghpages-with-orgmode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blogging-on-ghpages-with-orgmode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-did&#34;&gt;what i did&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;ve just moved from using markdown and jekyll to generate a static website on github pages to using org-mode and org-publish to generate static html files, also on github pages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-did-i-do-this&#34;&gt;why did i do this&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;my setup has been a pain - i do most of my writing and thinking in &lt;a href=&#34;https://orgmode.org/&#34;&gt;org mode&lt;/a&gt;, but to post stuff on &lt;a href=&#34;https://me.jowj.net/&#34;&gt;https://me.jowj.net/&lt;/a&gt; i have to convert that to markdown (relatively easy, due to a package called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/emacsmirror/org/blob/master/lisp/ox-md.el&#34;&gt;ox-md&lt;/a&gt;) and use &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt; to convert md to html and handle the generation of the site. the problem with jekyll is that it &lt;em&gt;sucks&lt;/em&gt;. its a tool based on the ruby ecosystem, and since I actually publish my stuff so infrequently every time i use it i have to update something about my ruby environment. this adds probably 10-20 minutes while I remember / look up which commands i&amp;rsquo;m supposed to run and why, and figuring out what things are actually broken this time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>emacs on catalina</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/emacs-on-catalina/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/emacs-on-catalina/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-days&#34;&gt;early days&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;i had to move from mojave to catalina during the beta to test some security tooling for work (spoilers: it sucked, though now cylance has actually fixed their catalina problems) and the process was r o u g h almost entirely because of emacs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;at first there was only a single reddit post detailing what emacs users might need to know about. it linked to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/dive/f64c645a9086afce8e5dd2590071dbf9&#34;&gt;this gist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;this basically says to run this lisp to add your proper emacs path to the proper exclusions and then you won&amp;rsquo;t have any problems. Ok great! but that didn&amp;rsquo;t work. I could now &lt;em&gt;launch&lt;/em&gt; emacs from Spotlight and navigate around my Docs/Downloads/whatever, but i was totally unable to &lt;em&gt;swap&lt;/em&gt; to emacs from Spotlight. this also impacted using hammerspoon as a launcher, i&amp;rsquo;m guessing because the primative behind both mechanisms is the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rest api prototyping</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/api-prototyping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/api-prototyping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-problem&#34;&gt;the problem&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;lately i&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a lot of web API glue projects. these are usually simple things like &amp;ldquo;service1 needs to send messages to service2 in a particular format, with a particular set of priviledges.&amp;rdquo; Sometimes its more complicated, but that&amp;rsquo;s usually what it breaks down to.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;at first I was writing python code the whole time, exploring the API through python (ugh) and kept getting frustrated; it felt like I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to go as fast as I would like, I kept making silly mistakes that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t catch until much later, etc. To fix this, i&amp;rsquo;ve moved to prototyping in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pashky/restclient.el&#34;&gt;restclient.el&lt;/a&gt; - this is a featureful rest client that you interact with through plain text (i.e., you can version control it!) within emacs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
